# Matthew Sawatzky

Winnipeg, MB | 204-226-3534 | matthewrsawatzky@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio

## **SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS**

Full Stack Web Developer experienced in front-end design and back-end programming. Strong communicator able to clearly and concisely share ideas and work well with others. Well versed in UI/UX design to create engaging and unique user experiences in a variety of styles. Skilled in several languages and frameworks with a strong proficiency in TypeScript and React. Acquired a range of industry skills through formal education, work experience and multiple completed projects.

## **SKILLS**

Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript; HTML/CSS, PHP; Java, Python, Ruby; SQL

Frameworks: React, Next.js, Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap CSS, Rails, Flask

Tools: Docker, Postman, Git, Prisma, Microsoft Office

Cloud Services: AWS, Firebase, Supabase

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

**BIZ BENEFITS** 

Winnipeg, MB

Full Stack Developer

Aug 2024 - Present

- Developed for a nationwide business improvement area benefits company offering deals and services to a consumer base of businesses and employees
- Pushed website to production with my development team where it now is serving thousands of businesses and employees across Canada
- Built and maintained features using JavaScript, React and Next.js
- Secured and tested all API Endpoints ensuring full website and data security
- Implemented Prisma ORM to manage business and payment data
- Worked with Cron jobs to automate subscription renewals and notifications
- Improved UI/UX in key forms and deals page to better reflect the company's identity and professionalism
- Worked in a development team participating in agile sprints, stand-ups and code reviews
- Led and facilitated client meetings to align project outcomes with stakeholder expectations

**BLUESKY FITNESS** 

Winnipeg, MB

Independent Front End Developer

Sep 2024 – Nov 2024

- Link: blueskyfitnessandhealthcoaching.vercel.app
- Created a TypeScript-based landing page utilizing react for a local fitness studio during spare time
- Developed a responsive and user-friendly fitness website to provide users with a comprehensive idea of the classes, personal training and benefits the studio offers
- Designed the website with a clean and straightforward layout to cater to an older client demographic, ensuring gym information was accessible and prominently displayed
- Worked closely with the client to meet their specific needs and requirements
- Implemented Tailwind CSS to create a cohesive and visually appealing website experience
- Enhanced the user experience while maintaining simplicity through adding smooth animations to key elements creating an engaging and dynamic interface

#### **EDUCATION**

## RED RIVER COLLEGE POLYTECHNIC

Winnipeg, MB

Full Stack Web Development

Aug 2023 - Sep 2024

Full Stack Web Development Diploma

Cumulative GPA: 3.8;

Relevant Coursework: Front-End Development, Back-End Development, Programming, Agile Development; Database Management, Web Security; Object-Oriented Design, Project Management, Business Requirements, IT Foundations; Communications

**Certifications & Training**: AWS Academy Cloud Foundations Certificate, Udemy React Training, Udemy Next.js Training